# Mohankumar Makuli Chandrayigowda

Liverpool, United Kingdom

\( +44 7833838626 \) mohankumar.mc@proton.me

in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohankumar-mc">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohankumar-mc</a>

https://github.com/Mohankumar-MC

# **Summary**

Graduate with a strong background in business and big data analytics who thinks strategically. Has experience using Python, SQL, Excel, and Tableau to improve business and give strategic insights. Proven skills in working as a team, paying attention to details, being flexible, working with people from different cultures, and carefully engaging stakeholders. Skilled at breaking down complicated ideas into insights that are easy to understand and use. I want to use a mix of technical skills, business sense, and strategic analysis to solve complex business problems in a role that is fast paced.

last pacea.

# Education

MSc in Business Analytics and Big Data (Merit) University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK Sep 2022 – Nov 2023

 Modules: Data Mining and Machine Learning, Big Data Management, Digital Business Technology, Big Data Analytics for Business, Digital Strategy, Enterprise Systems using SAP, Project and Portfolio Management, Sustainable Supply Chain Management.

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering (First-Class Honours) Visvesvaraya Technological University, India Aug 2016 – Sep 2020

 Modules: Mathematics, C Programming, Web Development Technologies, Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Object Oriented Programming, Big Data, Data Base Management Systems, Networking.

Skills

- Languages: Python, R, SQL, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.
- Tools: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAP HANA, YouTube Studio Analytics, Knime Analytics, IBM SPSS Statistics, Jupyter Notebook, git, Google Cloud Platform, VS Code, PyCharm.
- Frameworks: Angular, Node.js, Flask, JUnit, WordPress, and Spark.
- Libraries: pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn.
- Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork, Leadership, Project Management, Attention to Detail, Adaptability, Stakeholder Engagement, Summarizing Complex Ideas, Cross-Cultural Engagement.

# **Academic Projects**

# SAP S/4HANA 1809 Global Bike

MSc Business Analytics and Big Data

- New product cost estimation with itemized view and develop a discussion report accordingly.
- Performing end to end Material Management operation from creating, routing, cost estimation, mark price updates to view price changes.
- Performing cost control assessments of materials and comparison reports on both manual and system operation. (primary, secondary, services etc...)
- Successfully performed all case studies of S/4HANA 1809 Global Bike on MM, CO-PC, and PP.

Skills used – SAP S/4HANA, Reporting, Auditing, financial analysis.

Online Notice Board

B.E Computer Science

- Collaborated with the admin team on the university and implemented various features such as add, delete, and view options that streamlined the process of updating information on the online notice board, resulting in a 40% decrease in manual work at university.
- Improved the overall usability of the online notice board by integrating a responsive design that allowed users to access notifications and articles on different devices without any issues, resulting in 20% increase in mobile traffic.

Skills used - GitHub, MySQL Databases, Visual Studio, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Software Development.

# **Advanced Traffic Management System using Google Cloud**

**B.E Computer Science** 

- Developed and implemented an automated IR-sense based solution to dynamically shift traffic signals (red/green) using Raspberry Pi microcontrollers, reducing wait times at one junction "proof-of-concept" by 30%.
- Designed cloud-based storage system for all sensor data that informs the traffic status and provides priority passage for ambulances, increasing emergency response time by 40%.

Skills used - Git, Google Cloud, Python, Sensors identifications and Integration, Project Management, Scrum.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# **Work Experience**

# University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

# **Project 1: Ethical Issues of using AI in Business Operations** | PG Student Research Assistant

- Conducting a comprehensive systematic literature review on Al ethics debates, analysing over 50 academic articles and industry reports.
- Case study analysing the effect of innovative ERP systems on the business operations of Motor Oil Hellas.
- Identified and documented emerging ethical issues associated with the use of AI technologies, including privacy concerns and potential biases in decision-making processes.
- Developed a set of recommendations for companies to ensure ethical practices in their use of AI technologies based on analysis of publicly available cases.

Skills used - Research Skills, IBM SPSS, Data Analysis, Business Analysis, Project Management, Supply Chain Management.

# Infosys Ltd. Bengaluru, India

Dec 2020 – Jul 2022

#### Project 1: Content Creator and Educator, Client: Springboard and ETA | Al and ML Educator

- Trained hundreds of employees, senior members of organization and clients of Infosys Ltd. on methods and benefits of using Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in business operations
- Continuously upskilling in new technologies related to Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Data Science through online courses and industry conferences. Implemented new learnings into ongoing projects resulting in a reduction of manual effort by 15% and increased accuracy by over 25%.
- Created data dashboards, graphs, and visualizations using Tableau, communicating insights to stakeholders, product owners, and senior teams.
- Led knowledge sharing initiatives and crafted compelling case studies that led to beneficial outcomes, displaying adaptability and resilience.
- Helped maximum tech employees of particular DC to upskill in 3 months making them aware of AI and ML inspiring them with new technologies directly impacting long term goal of Infosys Nio.

Skills used – Python, EDA, ML, Project Management, Model Evaluation, Knime Analytics.

# Project 2: Zoiee , Client: Multiple Event Services (Chatbot) | Systems Engineer

- Restart and allocate virtual servers at Infosys Ltd. AI chatbot named Zoiee for different client events.
- Handling multiple clients simultaneously and providing services.

Skills used - Server Maintenance, Linux, Virtual Machines, Technical Support.

#### Project 3: GenQ, Client: Springboard | Systems Engineer Associate

- Implemented a responsive design for the complete user interface of a major project, resulting in increased user engagement by 40% and reducing bounce rates by 25%, which was featured in 'India Al 2021'.
- Collaborated with a team to structure and analyse business requirements, transforming them into functional specifications for developers and providing strategic solution.

Skills used - Git, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, Agile Methodologies.

\_\_\_\_\_

# **Achievements**

- Al and ML Educator at Infosys Global Education Center (world's largest corporate training centre).
- Business Communication level 5 certified.
- Infosys certified Executive program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.